okay sounds good and then let's move to
the technical part a deep neural network
for acoustic modeling uh is the today's
uh the
topic and actually today's topic covers
many things uh first uh the the the
basic approach of the how to apply deep
neural network for acostic modeling and
then uh I will also explain about the
several Advanced neural network uh the
the uh the acoustic model and the uh the
thecurrent neural network is usually the
covered in this Advanced neural network
acostic model but maybe this can be in
the uh next lecture uh my today's kind
of a goal is anyway to try to finish the
explanation about the CNN uh and so
on okay so uh today's agenda is for
acoustic
modeling so basically this is uh the
most acoustic modeling and partly cover
the feature extraction but it's not
about end to end but basic neur Network
part is of course applied to the N2
neural network so this part is actually
quite related to the entire
lecture first uh let's review the the
our acoustic
models so we have our the speech feature
observation uh sequence and the output
can be the token uh sequence it can be
word or character or subword depending
on our application and for the classical
the acoustic modeling speech we also
always kind of using the the pon
sequences and so on and then this uh
three variable can be decomposed to have
a three kind of factors uh and so
on and then today's uh the focus is this
acoustic mod part
and uh the the our costic model is
having a issue in the
lenss uh and then we try to kind of
mitigate this issue by introdu the HM
State sequence uh that is we spend a lot
of time to the study about this kind of
issue and so
on and then actually uh that in this uh
the lecture please uh understand that
the
output part how to kind of deal with the
output part is not so much changed we
just using
HML but input part or how to kind of
model the the speech features is
actually deed with the Deep neural
network so this is just partly using
deep neural network a power but the the
output ring part output sequential uh
the uh the problem is still based on the
hidden Mark
model so that's the kind of the high
level uh the the discussion in today's
the lecture and let's uh revisit our the
hmm
the uh the the discussion actually the
in the hmm discussion we are the by
using the hmm State sequence we mostly
the focus on the uh the P given is the
uh some hmm state in time frame T and
then corresponding the observation and
then we actually make the likely
function right and then which function
did we use here we use gaan Gaia mixure
model and so on and this is actually a
very strong constraint due to the EM
algorithm and so on we actually cannot
use the other other functions the so
much there's a few function we can use
it but basically we cannot use the other
function this is a big uh
restriction but as we discussed in the
last time in the CDC derivation uh we
just REM remove the constant of the EM
algorithm we just focus on the gradient
to optimize our parameters we can
actually remove this constraint and this
are the P given this part this part can
be actually replaced with the Deep neur
network but again the all the other part
is same and then this approach is called
the DNN hm hybrid
system so this the word o appeared so
please remember uh that I am using a DNM
hybrid hybrid people just call it the
hybrid system and so on but this means
that we still using the hmm uh we still
using the most of our formulation that
we used before like the beta algorithm
forward backward and so on however C
mixture part is repaced with the neural
network and so on and then there are lot
of ways to do that but this is the one
very typical way to use the kind of DNN
for the the instead of the gaan mixture
model actually deep new network is very
good at
classification classification means that
given the observation we will actually
predict which one is the kind of hmm
state or for and so on for character and
so on so we actually have a uh they can
make a very good neural network uh
classifier here and then and what we
usually are using in GMM is actually
opposite right observation is left this
one is observation is right so then we
actually can simply using the product
rule the the the or Bas the theem and
actually also by the way removing the
the another kind of the prior
information about observation and then
we can actually
converting this uh the the the the
probability uh with the the uh
likelihood but by dividing the prior so
this is a kind of only equation we need
and the PST is actually at the computer
by just kind of counting the the
observation of the state and so
on and the anyway the idea is that we
just focusing on this one in the Deep
neural network and then if we try to
convert it to the to with kind of our
GMM framework we just kind of dividing
by this the P SD uh the prior
distribution uh that's it and all our
the the the another the the the the uh
the the all our kind of uh the the
formulations are actually almost same
and luckily the forward backward to get
the kind of uh the the the occupation
probability and so on we can actually
still using this one neural network
output divided by the prior distribution
by the way M step is not used anymore so
this part is replaced with the the grad
Des Center but e step part we can still
use the the hmm algorithm and another
probably most important part is V
algorithm given the model we try to get
the kind of most likely sequence right
this one is again we can actually use a
hmm just by
dividing the the the again the the DNN
the
the the posterior uh the divided by the
uh this the prior distribution uh and so
on so by using this uh that we can
actually also using the hmm okay but how
how to get this kind of uh the uh DNN uh
the AIA we will be discussing okay so
now we actually using all kind of
problem P given St other PST given OT
and then let's think about they did try
to focusing on estimating this part and
it's actually uh becomes uh the the
problem of the given speech
feature to uh prct the hmm State
SD
okay
however as you know we don't have a
correct label for hmm
state it is the alignment can be are
there the uh the any
variations so we actually using the big
uh very big assumption which is just
using the B
alignment and then get some kind of a
the state uh the index for the each
frame and then using it as a
Target so uh this is a very big
approximation again because you know as
we discussed we really not sure we are
really not sure uh this alignment is
correct or
not and then uh bab alignment will
provide us the kind of most likely
alignment
uh but this is not the true and this is
alsoo obtained from the model so this is
actually one of the big approximation
but effectively this one is quite
working so uh DN and hmm is actually
based on this assumption and then the
all the kind of The Following part is
derived so this part is the the probably
the the most the difficult part for
everyone
to
understand I actually first time didn't
fly understand it so this means that we
need beta varment so we need some models
right and how to make a model we
actually using
Gan yeah so the this uh the
hmm uh DNN hybrid system is actually
depending on the previous GMM systems
and then get the B alignment and then
make the kind of the the uh the input
and output and then make a kind of
classifier uh and then people may also
do the the alignment based on B
alignment based on this kind of obtain
the DNA and so but it can be kind of a
the local Optimum right in terms of
alignment so that's why that some people
mention that the CTC or uh the the
attention can be better because this
assumption is too
strong okay so anyway uh that now we
know that the the input and
output input speech features it can be
log filter B that which you guys
implemented right and output is the the
hmm State again you guys also using it
for your kind assignment the coding
assignment it's the your case is simple
yes no uh but the uh it can be you know
many of the characters or many of the
subw depending on our system and so on
uh but anyway the input is this kind of
the speech features and output is the
ladio and then every time frame we use a
kind of deep neur Network crash fire to
predict the hmm state
okay very simple right very simple
problem after we get the bet arment the
very simple problem uh so that the since
it is simple and then just making a deep
new network to be kind of more
complicated uh that's that kind of
methodology is quite working in the
beginning of the the spech cognition
development now I will discuss more
about you know what is the input fature
uh and what is the kind other
intermediate representation in deep neur
Network in more
details so first uh the input
feature uh yes uh we use mlcc or L fi
bank but there is a big actually the
changes so we usually concatenate
several
frames uh so that the input becomes more
kind of Rich information
more context
information this is actually not so much
use for the
GMM because GMM we use diagonal Coan
right you remember that diagonal coant
right which is of diagonal element is
completely zero so this means that the
features should not be so
corated uh so the l f
and it's actually the the features some
correlation but it's quite
independent but the if we
concatenate are the neighboring
features the feature is actually very
highly cated with 10 millisecond the
feature is not so much changed so this
is actually not well the model in GAA
mixture however deep NE network doesn't
care we actually using the first linear
layer to consider the this kind of
correlation and so on so we can actually
input the the concatenated features so
that is actually one a big change from
the initial the gaussia mixture model to
the the Deep NE
Network and the people can concatenate
totally seven frames or 11 frames it's
very
long next part is the output which I
explained before anyway we use the bet
uh the algorithm and then get Okay cool
so uh the now that given this kind of
hmm State as an output let's try to make
a deep new network
classier and then uh Deep by uh new
network uh the through the discussion
with some of the student people are not
so much familiar with the Deep neur some
people are not very familiar with the
Deep neur Network so I am kind of a
showing some kind of a explanation uh
about the Deep neural network which is
basically the combination of the lot of
binary classifiers if using the sigmoid
activation
function deep neur network is again the
combination of the binary
classifier so binary classifier which is
a simple uh the problem to see whether
uh the our kind of data is the yes or no
uh the the circle or uh the the cross uh
in this uh Direction by the way this the
the mark uh would depend I heard that
this changes depend on the culture in
Japanese Circle means correct and the X
means the the wrong but probably other
people may have a
different way right yeah but please
understand circle is correct and the the
cross is
wrong and the um so I in this Cas the
cases I use a very kind of a simple
simple linear crash which is just kind
of uh the using the the sample to be
classified by using the linear function
and then to make this kind of to be more
kind of probabilistic distribution we
actually using the sigmoid function is a
kind of linear the function to make the
kind of the the the correct and wrong
the decision to be a
probability so this is a very simple
binary
classifier the people can understand it
I think so right okay
um this uh binary classifier we can also
make it by using the the gaan mixture
model and the by using the gaan mixture
model to actually get the lik of the
correct and wrong and then we use that
kind of
normalization and then making it the
probability and then we can make
actually uh the uh this one to be the
the probability of the yes and
no however it is getting more difficult
if the the
GMM for example it is not easy to
actually represent this kind of shape
other other the the gaan mixture model
maybe we could use this kind of way to
make it but it is not very easy for gaan
mixture model to make a very complicated
pattern
instead uh how neural network is
presenting this kind of pattern it's
actually combined the several crash fire
several binary crash fire if we combine
this kind of a shape the the binary
classification this binary
classification and this binary
classification we can actually present
this kind of very complicated crash
firers and this just kind of combine the
many of the binary crash fire and if we
have a more areas we can actually
represent many many complicated uh the
crass fires and so on and this is the
kind of the power of the neuron Network
instead of just using the one person
decision we using the you know many
people's decision not the people but
anyway my using the the several
decisions and then combine them to
actually other the uh present a
complicated
patterns and then uh this is just to
kind of make a kind of many kind of
combining various patterns but the Deep
network is actually also making the this
the pattern to be more complicated by
using the more layers so this kind of
actually combination is just having the
many kind of neurons here so just kind
of having a more the peoples here but
having a multiple layers means that we
have a more kind of meetings more
meetings more meetings to Define our
ideas and so on so this is actually uh
the the deep new network so basically it
comes from the the combination of the
binary crash fire but it's by combining
the the more people or more meetings uh
which corresponding to the more layers
and more neurons uh this becomes
actually quite the strong and then we
can actually finally make the very
complicated decision in our cases are
the speech condition condition like
every frame whether this one is that H
or a or or the HM State one and so on
that is a kind of deep neural network
and then let's go use a little bit Mass
about it for example by using the
complicated uh the the
nonlinear by using complicated
combination of the complicated the
activation is represented as Vector
representation uh Vector form so we have
a input of the the the neural net uh the
the speech features and then having a
linear
layer but this is actually the the
linear Matrix and the vector so this
means that instead of having a one crash
fire we actually having a a lot of Crash
firers combined so this actually this
equation corresponding to other correct
many people's
opinion and then uh given this one other
other in other input we will recursively
perform this uh decision several times
and then uh this kind of a the index l
means layer so this part is becomes deep
and then people started to call it the
Deep neuron
Network and then finally this uh the
activation is actually slow to the soft
marks the activation function which
actually converting the probability uh P
converting this kind of features to the
actually probability uh of the uh the in
the uh the space uh of uh this state uh
the or lels and so on before that we
only using the Sig mode so it's actually
corlection of the
binary but after the soft marks it
becomes for example the the one of the
probability uh in our vocabulary s and
so on so this is a kind of basic feed
for the neuron
Network and let's move to the uh each
the part of the
equations uh we actually have a three
part of the equation one is a a linear
the transformation the other is the
sigmoid function and the other is the
soft marks
functions and the first part is a linear
operation which is uh probably everyone
is familiar with that just using the the
matx to convert the speech features and
we often also using the bias vector and
so on and then this actually converting
it and and also the the linear operation
is used to kind of change the dimension
size from input to the part we want so
this is a kind of linear operation and
the linear operation as you may know
this since this is linear the derivative
is very simple uh we just you know take
the this one for the W in terms of w and
then we just having a derivative here
and if we take the derivative for the
bias we can also have this kind of
form okay so uh this is a kind of the
linear operation and note that this part
is since
Matrix so this is actually the the the
the quadratic in terms of the number of
parameters if if we try to have more
kind of neurons this Matrix size uh
becomes increased proportional to the
square of the original Dimension and so
on and then the actually uh the uh the
it's I saw that I make it at a short
quick but it's actually not um the the
go wider versus go deeper which are the
increase the parameters uh the more
so the uh the number of the
dimension go wider means the number of
Dimension becomes increase right and go
deeper means the number of layer becomes
deeper right and the uh actually uh the
go
wider and then due to this kind of the
property uh the mat
property generally the number of
parameters uh becomes the very large so
please be careful about control your
kind of models just making this part to
be very large and then it's the the
quite
large I think it's cannot will fit the
the your memory and so on instead making
it deeper either easy to control so
people usually actually are control the
number of layers for the architecture
rather than why the number of neutrons
and so
on okay and then the next function is a
sigmoid
function uh this uh the sigmoid function
is uh the very interesting probability
which is actually the making the any
numbers uh the mapping the any number to
0 to
one so this is actually very good to
kind of the model the probability of the
binary so if you know this is go to the
the some point the point like 0.7 which
mean 70% it would happen right and it
would not happen would be 30% l so the
one minus the sigma is actually the the
the the probability of the the negative
the the the event in the sigmoid
function uh and so on and the sigon by
the way uh the uh we should be careful
about the
notation uh from now on we often
actually have this kind of notation 1 +
e minus X
Vector usually exponential cannot accept
the vector right in the very
mathematical uh the beginning of the
mathematics that we learn it right log
also cannot accept the the vector in
general right but from now on uh let's
kind of accept that you know exponential
and the vector means that the
exponential performed for each element
of the vector so this one is also 1 + e
minus X rather the uh is oneid 1 plus e
minus X this means that actually Vector
of this operation for each component so
many people actually confuse this and
the same for the log and so on so please
uh do not confuse about it uh about this
oh the exponential with the the vector
is it is wrong it's actually yes in some
sense wrong but this actually expansion
of the uh the explanation about
it and then uh the derivative becomes
the this
interesting form Sigma
X parenthesis 1 minus Sigma X and so on
and
the if I have time I usually actually
demonstrate how the the the sigmo looks
like don't have so much time but anyway
that usually you know Sigma
x0 x = z and then what is the sigma zero
correct 0.5 right
0.5 so what is the sigma X when the x is
the the minus
infinity zero yes it's going to be like
this and what is the uh the X uh equals
the plus
infinity correct
one so sigar usually have this kind of
shapes and if we also have a gradient
and so on we can also have a more
discussion about this the shape and so
on but I just uh skip the the more
detailed discussion and so
on okay uh now that we will move to the
soft Mark function and this actually not
easy right but since it had more
Dimension and so on but actually uh this
one is uh the a kind of a extension of
the sigmoid function uh from the binary
to
multiple the labels and so on so for
example let's say the J is the entire
the vocabulary size and then the sigo uh
s sorry soft Marx function first mapping
any of this kind of value any of the
kind of value in h to the the between
zero and one so this is very similar to
the Sig
function and in addition sing mod
function a soft Mark function actually
satisfies the sum to one
condition is very similar to Sigma but
it's actually can also that apply to The
The J equal more than two so this this
the property is very similar to the
probability so that people using soft
Marx function as the way to converting
our the the values to the
probability by by the way it can be
anything it can be you know any other
function than Sigma and soft marks but
the which satisfy this condition we can
actually use it but Sigma is and softmax
is very good property when we get the
derivative and so on so that people
usually using the softmax function as a
kind of final part of getting the
probability uh and so
on so that's the the major are the the
functions that we use for the field for
neural
network but actually uh the uh this is
not
everything as some of you may know
actually we can use many of the
functions operation in the Deep neural
network we can actually using the L
exponential uh the
multiplication uh the sign
cosine the hyperbolic sign the almost
all the function we can actually use to
approximate our problems so this is
actually uh one reason that the um NE
network is very very powerful but the
one constent is whether we can take a
derivative uh and so on and this is
actually uh the the most of the function
we can take a derivative but the
actually the most basic operation AG
Marx which we can get the speech equ
result finally right this actually
doesn't get the derivative so this part
is actually they cannot are the used
inside the neural network and so on but
almost all the the operation we actually
get the derivative and then we can use
okay so final part is the objective
function
design and then object objective
function we usually using a cross
entropy uh this is actually uh the uh
definition is like this
uh one for the
reference and one for the
prediction and then using the cross
entropy this uh the means that it's
actually the just the substituting the
cross enthropy
definition and then it becomes this kind
of equation
form
however this reference part is actually
little bit unique form right this
difference part now is actually just
using the bet the betab
alignment and then making it the kind of
probability right this means that that
this part is actually just a chonic Dela
function where a label
is obtained by the the BET alignment or
not right so this actually summation
part is the then the
simplified by using this Chron Delta and
then this is the final form of the Cross
entropy function which is actually the
the
probability of the the BET align the
state
sequence the and the summation over the
T so it becomes actually the the uh the
the objective function of the Cross
entropy in the the hard alignment
cases of course that if we using the
soft alignment this part summation is
not cancelled out and we may actually
using the
summation keeping the summation to also
get the kind of cross eny objective
function and so on but in most cases
again we just using the hard label and
then this becomes just add like L
like but this is just one
possibility uh we could use many other
objective functions uh like the the
square error or the the other uh the the
the the form of the uh the output
representations and so on but the we
usually using the cross enthalpy for the
spech cases
so that's the uh the entire uh neural
network uh the design so we set the kind
of discuss the input and what is output
and then uh the the some of the neural
network functions inside and then the
loss function and then we can actually
get the derivative to update the
parameters and so on and that's the the
middle part is actually quite has a lot
of flexibility compared with the gaan
mixture models gausia mixture model the
flexibility would be like a number
of
mixtures are there any other
flexibility can we use a diagonal Coan
or good
Coan maybe something like that there a
few extensions we can make by the way
but that's kind of only uh the uh the
the the variations but uh new network is
basically can uh the using the any of
the the functions and then get the kind
of
derivative and then make a kind of a the
entire architecture so this flexibility
is actually quite
strong so in my lecture by the way I try
to uh use the rectangular block when we
have a trainable uh
parameters and the um landed rectangular
block when uh the uh it is uh without
trainable parameters like a sigmo soft
marks sign cosine log and so on this is
actually a rounded rectangular block I
try to kind of make it consistent but if
not I apologize for it please point out
it and then observation or some kind of
intermediate activation is kind of a
written as a circle but anyway the newer
network is again can be at any of the
kind of combination so wait a
moment this
one so we could actually you know uh the
even change the
uh change the order this is not very Mak
sense but actually this is one
possible
architecture and the um this is very
unable the the architecture because a
linear twice is actually can be written
as a one linear function this is very
redundant and makes the kind of
optimization difficult and also twice
activation function nonlinear activation
function twice also making the kind of
optimization very difficult so I don't
recommend to do that but yeah we can
have many ways to actually uh the the
design the uh the uh the architecture by
for example using the after the sigma we
use a one linear transformation and the
different linear transformation and then
concatenate this kind of other features
and then throw it the sigmoid function
the soft Mark Activation so on we can
actually design uh many of the kind of
neural network architecture so that's I
call it neural network engineering so
the from now on actually a lot of neural
network engineering happens uh that is a
kind of very different from the lectures
in the first part and the second
part okay the last part is given the uh
the the this architecture and we set the
loss function we actually all the
information are given and the the
problem is how to actually estimate the
parameters and so on and then we using
the gradient Center to the optimize the
the hyper parameter and then just a kind
of the
DAP uh this is the kind of a final loss
function cross entropy and then taking
the derivative to get some kind of a
derivative in terms of the all kind of
parameters and then the updating the the
the uh the new parameters from the old
one so this is uh the the the basic uh
the the the gradient desent and actually
we also already introduced it in the CTC
part where this cross entropy loss
function is replaced with the uh the the
CTC
L function and so on and this uh
derivative is
basically uh almost all functions we can
get by using the chain rule so please uh
the be familiar uh with the chain
rle uh the the one of the example of the
chain rle would be for example the the
sigmoid function this actually very
complicated uh the function but we can
get the
derivative uh by using this kind of
forms and the yeah again I was probably
the
okay okay it's fine yeah and if we take
the derivative of the sigmoid function
this one in terms of the B we first
using the chain rule to factorize the
derivative in terms of the sigmoid
function itself and the the argument of
the sigmoid function with the the this
derivative and as we see already in the
previous lecture or previous other pages
that the sigmoid function derivative is
Sigma Y and one minus Sigma Y and this
part of the derivative is actually one
so that this is the
answer and if we are the focus on the A
and then we we actually have the X
outside and then the rest is the same
and then by using the chain though uh we
can actually get the the derivative and
so on um so the actually the again chain
rule is very important so please
remember it uh my friends he was in a
company and he often ask the questions
to the other intern application
applicant that you know
for the intern he will ask the uh the
derivative of the sigmoid function and
see whether you know you guys can really
understand the chain Rule and so on so
if you master this part at least you
know his interview you can
pass please remember that yeah even I am
also asking you guys of for the chain
yeah and the uh the chainer can now be
that the performed recursively uh that
is actually the quite the strong part of
the getting the neural network just you
know the composing the function and then
the taking the derivative for each of
the the component by the chain rule we
can get actually the derivative and so
on and then we can update the
parameters and the uh the last part of
the optimization oh no not the last part
but the another remarks of the
optimization
is uh when we taking this
derivative can we take this derivative
for each sample or can we take the the
this deriva for
entire uh the data or we can use
something
between actually the EM algorithm is as
you remember we take the kind of a uh
the uh the the up dat parameter by using
the old data
right uh which is actually very slow in
terms of the convergence but the since
the the uh the EM algorithm is very kind
of a good nature of the convergence and
also GMM is the Computing is faster so
people usually using the PCH
processing uh but the uh another
approach is uh taking the every exle and
then getting the derivative and so
on this is actually very
inefficient uh since this the this part
is are the incremental so we actually
cannot paralyze them and then however
this is basically very fast in terms of
the
convergence and then miniat processing
is doing something
between so let's say for example we have
you know 10,000 sample data we just
divided data to S each
the sample to be thousand and then
making a mini so that each the miniat we
actually have a good the polarization
property efficient and across the miniat
we updating the parameters and then we
can get a kind of faster convergence
than the batch processing so that the
mini batch processing is very important
uh to make the kind of neural network to
get our kind of reasonable performance
however the size of size of the miniat
is very very important and then I think
the oh okay okay I skip I I forgot but I
skip it this so the original Short quiz
was actually this mini B size that
affect the performance and so on and the
answer is yes so this
sorry but I I actually suddenly changed
the another question we have still seven
minutes right yeah but we still don't go
to the CNN okay um so um minat
processing is again the uh quite
important hyper parameters
it's the in addition to kind of a
control
convergence and the the effective n of
the a polarization of the
computation miniat size is also
affecting the memory GP memory and so on
right so mini is and the mini size is
also depending on the sum of the
operation like the the uh the B norm and
so on this is Advanced topic but anyway
the the B the norm or the convergence
speed and the the effect iess of the
paration and the memory side so this
miniat side is very difficult to
tune and actually uh this is the most
important part uh of the uh the uh the
getting the kind of reasonable
performance so please remember that this
one is a one of the most important hyper
parameter in deep NE
Network and then again I have one story
now
are the many people moving to the Deep
new network right and then some people
may you know just you know knowing the
Deep new network but don't know so much
about actually doing some optimization
there such people exist right you know
just knowing but has never you know
tried the the things actually and so on
we can easily detect such people so we
can just ask
mze mze is again very important if
people are actually working on the
program we have to tune we have to
understand our problem we have to
understand all kind of the the the the
the computer configurations and so on
then again you know the the people don't
have they never touch deep running but
just know they knowing Deep Run your
network and you know they explain
something about it and then you know
again if you guys want to see whether he
or she is really knowing the de new
network just asking asking the parze if
they cannot answer that person actually
doesn't touch the Deep NE
Network
okay so next uh the hyper parameter is
the learning
GR in addition to this uh data uh back
propagation gradient part there is a one
hyper parameter here which is the
controlling the uh the the learning the
behavior by the way this one is also the
similar to the mini because mini also
kind of a control the scaling and so on
but anyway this kind of a the setting
the learning rate is the very difficult
and the there are lot of ways to some
level optimizing the learning rate but
the uh
this the optim imization usually doesn't
have any answer for the scating and so
on at least the scating level we have to
tune
this the learning date and so and this
is the most easiest way to the tune the
learning behaviors so uh that I want to
mention emphasize it because from now on
you will you know doing some kind of new
architecture implementing it and it's
working well usually we have to chune
the other this other parameter otherwise
uh your architecture might be correct
but due to the kind of the the the the
missing of the Learning grade you guys
may not have a full kind of a power of
your new architecture and so on so this
is unfortunate but anyway try to tune
the learning rate if it doesn't work
well and then uh this is actually
the second quit so this is uh the the uh
this side TOS the training accuracy
higher is better this one is validation
accuracy high as better and this one
again the training accuracy and the
variation accuracy higher is better and
then the uh question is which one is
better in terms of the training Behavior
that's
short the answer is yes now they the
same scale and then of course right
right side better right but
I I want you to I want you not to answer
this because the my intention is the gap
of the training
validation uh the the right side the
training the validation is very similar
right similar behavior and left side
training and valuation behavior is very
different right uh this is actually
happens in the typical
overtraining and then this actually
quite often happens uh the how to
mitigate this issue we can just reduce
the running rate this is very important
so that the police remember this trick
and so
on okay so I couldn't move to the other
CNN but anyway I can finish the the
basic neural network part yeah thank you
so much